Devin Hansen

Irving, Texas | Email: hansdevi@isu.edu | Phone: (208) 300-7600 LinkedIn: hansdevi@isu.edu | Phone: (208) 300-7600

SUMMARY

An adaptable and eager to learn Per Scholas graduate with ample experience and recent education/training in the field of computer programming. Former sales professional with over 10 years of experience in customer service, communication, teamwork, and interpersonal skills. A creative thinker with a detail-oriented drive to find new and improved ways to solve problems. Top strengths: Adaptability, Analytical, Intellection, Deliberative, Belief (source: Gallup Clifton Strength Coaching)

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Foundational knowledge of computer programming using HTML, CSS, Python, JavaScript, Document Object Model (DOM), Object-Oriented Programming (OOP), React/Redux, Express, Node.js, and Unix Shell (Udacity Nano-Degree program 2022)(PerScholas Software Engineering program, presently enrolled)
- Adobe Premiere video editing software
- Microsoft Word, Excel, Google Drive, Google Sheets, Google Docs, Google Slides, Gmail
- Proficient in use of Zoom & social media platforms including Facebook, Instagram & YouTube
- Operating Systems: Windows 7, Windows 10, Windows Vista, Windows 8, Mac OSX

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

RoadTripCentral – Arlington, Virginia & Irving, Texas Owner & Automotive Videographer

Feb. 2018 – Present

Commissioned automotive videographer and visual storyteller

- Create artistic video content and script with subject matter expertise about unique/rare performance cars to be used as informative/entertaining material for social media, as well as sentimental keepsake videos for vehicle owners
- Leverage creative, complex technology platforms such as Adobe Premiere Pro to create unique, standout videos
- Develop creative social media content for multiple platforms including Instagram and YouTube to gain thousands of interactions and engagements with online audience

U.S. Census Bureau – Irving, Texas Enumerator (Seasonal)

Aug. 2020 – Oct. 2020

Census enumerator for non-response follow-up operation

- Visited 125+ single home and multi-home residences weekly to gather demographic information to be used in the 2020 U.S. Census
- Utilized mobile technology applications to interview residents in assigned areas, explain the purpose of the Census, answer their questions/concerns, and record their responses to assist U.S. government in accurately allocating resources to areas based on metrics

Lindsay Cadillac – Alexandria, Virginia Automotive Sales Consultant

March 2017 – Feb. 2018

High-performing & award-winning automotive dealership with 300-vehicle inventory locally

- Used Customer Relationship Management System to develop and maintain relationships with 40+ prospective customers at any given time via email, voicemail, and text messages
- Contributed to the development of 4 new employees with automotive subject matter expertise
- Provided hundreds of in-depth vehicle feature demonstrations to new and prospective customers

Enterprise Holdings – Alexandria & Arlington, Virginia Management Trainee

Sept. 2015 - March 2017

World's largest rental car company with award-winning customer service

- Mastered and utilized Rental Management System applications such as Odyssey and ECARS 2.0
 while individually completing 300+ rental transactions per month at Arlington's highest-grossing
 rental location
- Learned and demonstrated mechanical and technological automotive features to customers.
- Assisted in the development and training of 5 new management trainees

Idaho State University Public Safety – Pocatello, Idaho Lead Dispatcher & Student Dispatcher

March 2014 – Aug. 2015

Public university with over 13,000 students and staff on campus

- Created & corrected 50+ digital incident reports in emergency situations on a weekly basis to adhere to the strict guidelines set forth by the Clery Act & Title IX, which outlines procedures for campus safety & harassment reporting protocols
- Managed over 600 Closed-Circuit Television (CCTV) cameras and campus alarm systems throughout the entire 80+ building college campus
- Supervised and provided leadership and assistance to 6 student dispatch team members, including but not limited to: providing technology and policy training, correcting errors in reports, evaluating productivity, interviewing student applicants, etc.

EDUCATION

Software Engineer Course

Feb. 2023 - Present

PerScholas - Dallas, Texas

Projected Graduation - May 2023

- Learned and implemented subjects such as NodeJS, HTML, CSS, Javascript, DOM, OOP, React, Redux, GitBash, Express, MongoDB, etc. (by end of course)
- Complete 450+ hours (by end of course) of hands-on daily coding in the MERN stack.

Bachelor of Science in Music

Aug. 2015

Idaho State University - Pocatello, Idaho

ACTIVITIES, LEADERSHIP & AFFILIATIONS

Lindsay Cadillac

 Regularly consulted with regarding any questions/inquiries regarding technical specifications of inventory

Enterprise

- Ranked #1 of 20 employees in competitive performance matrix multiple times in calendar year
- Regularly recognized as a top 10 sales performer (out of 80+ employees) in monthly regional Enterprise performance matrix (Regions 16YY and 16UU) due to outstanding customer service & salesmanship

U.S. Census Bureau

Frequently recognized as #1 team leader with highest rate of case closure rate per hour

ISU Extracurricular

• Served as the Choral Tenor Section Leader, led 8-12 singers by functioning in a leadership role in a team environment to assist the director in efficiently and effectively obtaining predetermined rehearsal goals while paying close attention to group dynamics and individual needs